<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ENCOR :: Ping-Square.com</title>
    <link>https://ping-square.com/ccnp-enterprise/encor/index.html</link>
    <description>Part I Forwarding&#xA;Chapter 1: Packet Forwarding Part II Layer&#xA;Chapter 2: Spanning Tree Protocol&#xA;Chapter 3: Advanced STP Tuning&#xA;Chapter 4: Multiple Spanning Tree Protocol&#xA;Chapter 5: VLAN Trunks and EtherChannel Bundles&#xA;Part III Routing&#xA;Chapter 6: IP Routing Essentials&#xA;Chapter 7: EIGRP&#xA;Chapter 8: OSPF&#xA;Chapter 9: Advanced OSPF&#xA;Chapter 10: OSPFv3&#xA;Chapter 11: BGP&#xA;Chapter 12: Advanced BGP&#xA;Chapter 13: Multicast</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 23:04:58 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ping-square.com/ccnp-enterprise/encor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6</title>
      <link>https://ping-square.com/ccnp-enterprise/encor/chapter-6/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 09:03:50 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ping-square.com/ccnp-enterprise/encor/chapter-6/index.html</guid>
      <description>IP routing Essentials 1) What is an AS? Answer An AS or Autonomous System (AS) is a connected group of IP networks managed by a single administrative entity, such as a university, government or a commercial organization.&#xA;2) What is an IGP? Answer An IGP or Interior Gateway Protocol is protocol that works best for the communication between IP networks within a single AS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding EIGRP</title>
      <link>https://ping-square.com/ccnp-enterprise/encor/chapter-7/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 15:18:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ping-square.com/ccnp-enterprise/encor/chapter-7/index.html</guid>
      <description>Understanding EIGRP Do you know about the EIGRP (RFC 7868) protocol? Let’s find out!&#xA;1) Can you explain the main advantages of using EIGRP in a network? Answer The main advantages of EIGRP include:&#xA;fast convergence due to the use of the Diffusing Update Algorithm (DUAL) and its partial updates. scalability in large networks, support for unequal-cost load balancing. classless routing Support for VLSM 2) What type of routing protocol is EIGRP? Answer EIGRP is a hybrid routing protocol, meaning it combines the characteristics of both distance-vector and link-state protocols. I is more efficient, supports faster convergence, and uses a composite metric based on bandwidth, delay, load, and reliability.EIGRP only exchanges information about paths and has lower overhead in large networks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding OSPF</title>
      <link>https://ping-square.com/ccnp-enterprise/encor/chapter-8/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 12:11:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ping-square.com/ccnp-enterprise/encor/chapter-8/index.html</guid>
      <description>So you think you know the OSPF protocol? Let’s find out!&#xA;RFC 2328&#xA;RFC 2328 RFC 2328 RFC 5340&#xA;RFC 5340 RFC 5340 1) What does OSPF stand for and what is its primary function? Answer OSPF stands for Open Shortest Path First. It is an open standard link-state routing protocol used for finding the best path between the source and the destination router using the shortest path first algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 14</title>
      <link>https://ping-square.com/ccnp-enterprise/encor/chapter-14/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 23:04:58 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ping-square.com/ccnp-enterprise/encor/chapter-14/index.html</guid>
      <description>Quality of Service (QoS) 1. What are the leading causes of QOS? Answer The leading causes of quality issues:&#xA;Lack of bandwidth Latency and jitter Packet loss 2. What are the most common causes of network latency? Answer The most common causes of network latency are:&#xA;Propagation delay (fixed) Serialization delay (fixed): is the time it takes to place all the bits of a packet onto a link. Processing delay (fixed): is the fixed amount of time it takes for a networking device to take the packet from an input interface and place the packet onto the output queue of the output interface. The processing delay depends on factors such as the following: CPU speed (for software-based platforms) CPU utilization (load) IP packet switching mode (process switching, software CEF, or hardware CEF) Router architecture (centralized or distributed) Configured features on both input and output interfaces Delay variation (variable): also referred to as jitter, is the difference in the latency between packets in a single flow. 3. What are the different QoS implementation models? Answer there are 3 QoS implementation models:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>